Bob Considine Papers
Bob Considine Papers
- Manuscripts
  - Manuscripts by Considine
    - Books
      - They Gave Us Wings [unpublished], alternate title, "They Gave You Wings"
        - Background material, 1970-1971 (Box 42)
        - Draft [I], typescript (Box 42)
        - Draft, 2 folders; typescript (Box 42)
        - Miscellaneous draft fragments (Box 42)
      - Toots
        - Draft, typescript (Box 42)
        - Miscellaneous material, includes correspondence, article "My Boss, Toots Shor" by Zigmund Krajewski (as told to Martin Scott) and chapter 8 draft (Box 42)
    - Broadcasts, scripts for Considine's "On the Line" radio show
      - Broadcasts, 1951 (Box 43)
      - Broadcasts, 1952 (Box 43)
      - Broadcasts, 1953 (Box 43)
      - Broadcasts, 1954 (Box 43)
      - Broadcasts, 1955 (Box 43)
      - Broadcasts, 1956 Jan-May (Box 43)
      - Broadcasts, 1957 (Box 43)
      - Broadcasts, 1962 (Box 43)
      - Broadcasts, undated (Box 43)
    - Interviews
      - Cronkite, Walter, 1975; includes galley (Box 43)
      - Franco, Francisco, undated (Box 43)
      - MacArthur, Douglas, 1954 (Box 43)
    - Movie scripts
      - "Babe", love story between Babe Didrikson and George Zaharias; outline (Box 43)
      - "The Beginning or the End", undated; 1974 film about the development of the atomic bomb, story by Considine (Box 43)
      - "Hoodlum Empire", undated; 1954 movie about organized crime, story by Considine (Box 43)
      - [Bound volume], MGM Pictures "Church of the Good Thief", 1944 (story by Considine); "The Beginning or the End" 1945-1946 (story by Considine); "The Beginning or the End", final version 1946; "Thirty Seconds Over Tokyo" by Dalton Trumbo, 1943 (based on Considine's book) (Box 44)
    - Obituary, Dwight D. Eisenhower, undated; prewritten (Box 44)
    - Report on the Inquiry of Bruno Shaw charges, by Considine and Cecil Brown, [1950s?]; regarding allegations of Communism (Box 44)
    - Screenplay, "The Man Who Changed Faces", 1956; story by Considine, screenplay by Guy Morgan (Box 44)
    - Speeches, 1966; undated (Box 44)
    - Stories
      - 1970 Trip (Box 44)
      - Asylum (Box 45)
      - The Beggar (Box 45)
      - [Biafra], 1968-1970; story and background material (Box 45)
      - Death of an Afternoon, undated; with Milt Kaplan (Box 45)
      - Destiny (Box 45)
      - Eyebrows, 1927 (Box 45)
      - Or a Reasonable Facsimile, by Considine and Peter Finney, 2 copies (Box 45)
      - Sentiment vs Sentimentality, 1927 (Box 45)
      - Test (Box 45)
      - Upon what Meat…?, 2 copies (Box 45)
      - Miscellaneous untitled, undated (Box 45)
    - Television shows, 1953; undated (Box 45)
  - Manuscripts by others
    - Articles
      - Abramsky, Samuel, "The Battle of Megiddo" (Box 45)
      - Brokaw, Tom, "The White House A.N., After Nixon" (Box 45)
      - Brooks, Betty M., "The Co-Founder of AA and me; Ten Years of AA at Wallkill Prison" (Box 45)
      - Brooks, Bill, [untitled], 1966 (Box 45)
      - Buttinger, Muriel M., "The Search for Jekelfalusi" (Box 45)
      - Canham, Erwin D., "Shutters are Closed", 1956 (Box 45)
      - Carney, Frederick S., "Crisis of Conscience in Dallas" (Box 45)
      - Chamberlain, John, "Resource Management and the Energy Picture", 1974; 2 copies (Box 45)
      - Cook, Hettie Milam, "Pathways to the Pit" (Box 45)
      - Corson, John J. and McConnell, John W., "Economic Needs of Older People" (Box 45)
      - Crockett, Albert Stevens, "Thanks to W. Clark Russell" (Box 45)
      - de Gripenberg, George (Baron), "A Close-Up of Pius XII" (Box 45)
      - Dutt, R. Palme, "An Anti-Marxist Book on the Jewish Question", 1958 (Box 45)
      - Ehrman, Anita, [untitled piece on U Thant] (Box 45)
      - Farrell, Thomas F., "More About the Atomic Bomb", 1946 (Box 45)
      - Fenerty, Clare Gerald, "Mrs. Shaw and the Irish" (Box 45)
      - Finnegan, Frank D.X., "1965 College Graduates - The Road to Success Isn't Through Short Work Week" (Box 45)
      - Finney, Ben, "Tall Tales but True" (Box 45)
      - Goodman, Leonard Lewin-Murray, [untitled] (Box 45)
      - Griffin, John David, "The Gettysburg Address as it would have been given by President Eisenhower" (Box 45)
      - Hearst, William Randolph Jr., [untitled], 1958; 1974 (Box 45)
      - Hubbell, John, "The Affair of the Vanishing Pesos" (Box 45)
      - Hurley, Robert, "Leukemia Speaking" (Box 45)
      - Isaacs, Bob, [untitled] (Box 45)
      - Leonidov, A., "Behind the Screen of Zionism", 1957 (Box 45)
      - McCarthy, Ellen Lucid, [untitled] (Box 45)
      - McLaren, Robert, [untitled] (Box 45)
      - McMillan, George S., "The Cocktail Party as a Social Institution - Its Place in the Modern World", 1958 (Box 45)
      - Meigs, Merrill C. [series of articles on WWII war surplus material] (Box 45)
      - Nichols, May Canan, "The Killer Who Never Fails" (Box 45)
      - Ramelson, Bert, "Socialism & the Jewish Question", 1958 (Box 45)
      - Reddy, John, "Danny Thomas Keeps a Promise" (Box 45)
      - Reddy, John, "The Unconquerable Gertrude Ederle", undated (Box 45)
      - Smedley, Arthur A. Jr., "T/SGT Richard J. Patton", 1957 (Box 45)
      - Smith, Kingsbury, [untitled], [1970] (Box 45)
      - Stripling, Robert E., edited by Considine [series of 28 articles regarding communism in the United State], undated (Box 46)
      - Thomas, Lowell, "Unforgettable Captain Eddie Rickenbacker", undated (Box 46)
      - Van Nest, Melvina E., [untitled] (Box 46)
      - West, William I., "Military and Education" (Box 46)
      - Zotos, Helen, "Iron Curtain Newsnotes" (Box 46)
      - Miscellaneous, undated; untitled items and fragments (Box 46)
    - Books
      - Moore, Robin (with Milt Machlin), "The Family Man", 1974; 4 folders (Box 46)
    - Interviews
      - Krushchev, Nikita (with Frank Conniff) (Box 47)
      - Ulbricht, Walter (with William Randolph Hearst Jr.) (Box 47)
    - Memorandum to Prospective Faculty Members of the Famous Writers School, undated (Box 47)
    - Outlines of Basic Course and Five Elective Courses, Famous Writers School, undated (Box 47)
    - Poems, 1936-1959; undated (Box 47)
    - Scripts
      - Forging Aerospace Power, The Story of the Air Force Command, 1962 (Box 47)
      - Hayden, Ross, "Tough Guy" [stories of Boystown] (Box 47)
    - Speeches, 1954; 1958 (Box 47)
    - Stories
      - Borodin, George, "Curves for Inferiority Complex" (Box 47)
      - Considine, John W. Jr. and Wyss, Martha, "Hollywood Miracle for a London Slum" (Box 47)
      - Fawcett, James Waldo, "Hurricane Law" (Box 47)
      - Fulbright, Freeman, "Douglas the Dissenter (or) A Durocher in a Long Black Robe" (Box 47)
      - Getchell, Ernest E., "Continuation of a Story of Escape from German Prison Camps as told by Sergeant Lee Gordon", 1950 (Box 47)
      - Gordon, Lee (as told to James H. Winchester) [2 untitled stories], undated (Box 47)
      - Haskin, Helen, "Thanksgiving Kitten" (Box 47)
      - Lawson, Ted. W. "Thirty Seconds over Tokyo", 1947 (Box 47)
      - McCann, Dick, "The Ulcer Half", 1951 (Box 47)
      - Winters, Bruce, [5 stories], From Out of the Past; A Load of Hay; Lost, One Heart; Stay Home; The Wart (Box 47)
      - Unknown author, "An Admirable Monomaniac", 1926 (Box 47)
      - Unknown author, "Do You Remember the Zeppelins?" (Box 47)
      - Unknown author, "Guatemala" (Box 47)
      - Unknown author, "Minor Leaguer" (Box 47)
      - Unknown author, "Sgt. 'Shorty' Gordon Story" (Box 47)
      - Unknown author, possibly Considine (Box 47)
      - Unknown author, possibly Considine (Box 48)
    - Stories for television show, undated (Box 48)
    - Story fragments, undated (Box 48)
- Memorabilia
  - Scrapbooks
    See also Subject files: Photographs: Scrapbook, Trans World Airlines Super-G Constellation International Preview Flight and Subject files: Photographs: Scrapbook, Trip to Russia
    - "Book #3", Jan 4, 1937 - Oct 1, 1938 (Oversize 27)
    - "Book #4", Oct 7, 1939 - Apr 1940 (Oversize 28)
    - [Untitled], Apr 20, 1940 - Dec 31, 1942; includes press badges dated 1938-1944 (Oversize 29)
    - [Untitled], Jan 1943 - Nov 1945; includes material from 1941-1942 as well (Oversize 30)
    - [Untitled], May 1943 - Feb 1950 (Oversize 31)
    - [Untitled], Dec 1946 - July 31, 1947 (Oversize 32)
    - [Untitled], Aug 1947 - Feb 1948 (Oversize 33)
    - [Untitled], Jan 1, 1948 - Dec 31, 1948 (Oversize 34)
    - [Untitled], Jan 1949 - June 30, 1951 (Oversize 35)
    - [Untitled], July 1, 1951 - July 31, 1952 (Oversize 36)
    - [Untitled], Sep 7, 1952 - Dec 1952 (Oversize 37)
    - "Entry for: William Randolph Hearst Jr., Bob Considine, Frank Conniff", presentation scrapbook for unspecified entry about their 1957 trip to the Soviet Union, meeting with Nikita Krushchev, and published newspaper stories about the visit (Oversize 38)
  - Miscellaneous memorabilia (Oversize 3)
- Newspaper column, On the Line
  All of these are typescripts, as submitted/transmitted to the news agency. A few have notes, annotations, or corrections. Undated columns have (where possible) been filed in the approximate correct location based on searches of newspaper databases to find publication dates.
  - On the Line, 1945 Sep, Nov, Dec (Box 48)
  - On the Line, 1946 Jan, Mar, May, Jul-Sep, Dec; 3 folders (Box 48)
  - On the Line, 1947 Jan-Mar; 5 folders (Box 48)
  - On the Line, 1947 May-Jul, Sep-Dec; 6 folders (Box 49)
  - On the Line, 1948 Feb (Box 49)
  - On the Line, 1949 Jun-Jul, Nov; 2 folders (Box 49)
  - On the Line, 1950 Jan-Apr; 3 folders (Box 49)
  - On the Line, 1950 May-Dec; 8 folders (Box 50)
  - On the Line, 1951 Jan-Feb; 2 folders (Box 50)
  - On the Line, 1951 Mar-Nov; 8 folders (Box 51)
  - On the Line, 1951 Dec; 2 folders (Box 52)
  - On the Line, 1952 Jan-May; 8 folders (Box 52)
  - On the Line, 1952 Jun-Jul, Sep-Dec; 7 folders (Box 53)
  - On the Line, 1953 Jan-Aug; 6 folders (Box 53)
  - On the Line, 1953 Sep-Dec; 4 folders (Box 54)
  - On the Line, 1954 (Box 55)
  - On the Line, 1955 Jan-Oct; 11 folders (Box 55)
  - On the Line, 1955 Oct-Nov; 2 folders (Box 56)
  - On the Line, 1956 Feb-Apr, Jul-Dec; 7 folders (Box 56)
  - On the Line, 1957 Feb-Jun; 6 folders (Box 56)
  - On the Line, 1957 Jul-Oct; 10 folders (Box 57)
  - On the Line, 1957 Oct-Dec; 5 folders (Box 58)
  - On the Line, 1958 Jan-Mar; 5 folders (Box 58)
  - On the Line, 1958 Mar-Nov; 11 folders (Box 59)
  - On the Line, 1958 Nov-Dec; 3 folders (Box 60)
  - On the Line, 1959 Jan-Mar; 7 folders; includes short series on Russia/Communism, "Our moment of peril," in March (Box 60)
  - On the Line, 1959 Apr-Sep; 12 folders; includes two short series, "A talk with Mr. Truman" and "J. Edgar Hoover: A Considine close-up," in May (Box 61)
  - On the Line, 1959 Oct-Dec; 6 folders (Box 62)
  - On the Line, 1960 Jan-Feb; 3 folders (Box 62)
  - On the Line, 1960 Mar-Jul; 11 folders; includes short series, "What's happening to Japan," in June; July has extensive coverage of Democratic and Republican conventions (Box 63)
  - On the Line, 1960 Jul-Nov; 9 folders (Box 64)
  - On the Line, 1960 Nov-Dec; 3 folders (Box 65)
  - On the Line, 1961 Jan-Apr; 9 folders; includes short series about astronauts, "Those 7 daring young men," in January and February (Box 65)
  - On the Line, 1961 Apr; short series, "Eichmann: Crime and Punishment" (Box 66)
  - On the Line, 1961 May-Sep; 9 folders (Box 66)
  - On the Line, 1961 Sep-Dec; 7 folders (Box 67)
  - On the Line, 1962 Jan; 2 folders (Box 67)
  - On the Line, 1962 Feb-Jun; 10 folders (Box 68)
  - On the Line, 1962 Jul-Nov; 9 folders; includes short series, "America's Gandhi: Martin Luther King," in September (Box 69)
  - On the Line, 1962 Dec; 2 folders (Box 70)
  - On the Line, 1963 Jan-May; 8 folders (Box 70)
  - On the Line, 1963 May-Aug; 9 folders; includes two short series, "John XXIII: His life and works" and "Pope Paul VI: Man and mission," in June (Box 71)
  - On the Line, 1963 Sep-Dec; 8 folders (Box 72)
  - On the Line, 1964 Jan (Box 72)
  - On the Line, 1964 Jan-May; 9 folders (Box 73)
  - On the Line, 1964 Jun-Oct; 9 folders (Box 74)
  - On the Line, 1964 Oct-Dec; 5 folders (Box 75)
  - On the Line, 1965 Jan-Mar; 5 folders (Box 75)
  - On the Line, 1965 Mar-Aug; 10 folders (Box 76)
  - On the Line, 1965 Sep-Dec; 8 folders (Box 77)
  - On the Line, 1966 Jan; 2 folders (Box 77)
  - On the Line, 1966 Feb-Jun; 11 folders; includes partial short series, "Autos, safety and your life," in February (Box 78)
  - On the Line, 1966 Jul-Nov; 10 folders; includes short series, "Inside the think tanks," in August (Box 79)
  - On the Line, 1966 Nov-Dec; 2 folders (Box 80)
  - On the Line, 1967 Jan-Jul; 7 folders (Box 80)
  - On the Line, 1967 Aug-Dec; 7 folders; includes short series, "Viet Nam: Victory or stalemate?" in September (Box 81)
  - On the Line, 1968 Jan-Feb; 3 folders (Box 81)
  - On the Line, 1968 Feb-Sep; 10 folders (Box 82)
  - On the Line, 1968 Oct-Dec; 3 folders (Box 83)
  - On the Line, 1969 Jan-Sep; 9 folders (Box 84)
  - On the Line, 1969 Oct-Dec; 3 folders (Box 85)
  - On the Line, 1970 Jan-May; 5 folders (Box 85)
  - On the Line, 1970 Jun-Dec; 8 folders (Box 86)
  - On the Line, 1971 Jan (Box 86)
  - On the Line, 1971 Feb-Sep; 8 folders (Box 87)
  - On the Line, 1971 Oct-Dec; 3 folders (Box 88)
  - On the Line, 1972 Jan-Mar; 5 folders; includes Nixon's trip to China (Considine was part of the press corps that accompanied him) and then Japan in February and March (Box 88)
  - On the Line, 1972 Apr-Oct; 7 folders; includes Considine travel to Japan, Russia, Poland in April (Box 89)
  - On the Line, 1972 Nov-Dec; 4 folders (Box 90)
  - On the Line, 1973 Jan-Apr; 6 folders (Box 90)
  - On the Line, 1973 May-Oct; 11 folders (Box 91)
  - On the Line, 1973 Nov-Dec; 4 folders (Box 92)
  - On the Line, 1974 Jan-Apr; 8 folders (Box 92)
  - On the Line, 1974 May-Oct; 12 folders; includes Nixon's trip to Israel in June (Considine was part of the press corps that accompanied him) (Box 93)
  - On the Line, 1974 Nov-Dec; 4 folders (Box 94)
  - On the Line, 1975 Jan-Apr; 8 folders (Box 94)
  - On the Line, 1975 May-Sep; 5 folders (Box 95)
  - Undated or misdated (Box 95)
- Published materials
  - Advertisements
    - Advertising featuring Considine (Box 96)
    - Advertising featuring Considine, oversize (Oversize 1)
  - Articles by Considine
    - Always a Gentleman, The Call Board, Jun 1957 (Box 96)
    - Babe Ruth as I Remember Him, Sports World, Sep. 1949 (Box 96)
    - Beau Pummel, Collier's, 14 Nov 1942 (Oversize 4)
    - Bob Considine Interviews Don Ho, Mainliner, Sep 1970; 2 copies (Box 96)
    - Bob Considine Reports, Las Vegas Magazine, 1 Nov 1951 (Box 96)
    - Broadway Columnist, Cosmopolitan, Jul 1951; 2 copies (Box 96)
    - Broadway Cop, Collier's, 20 Dec 1941 (Oversize 4)
    - Brother Matthias and Babe Ruth, by babe Ruth as told to Bob Considine, Oct 1948; condensed chapter from Considine's Babe Ruth book (Box 96)
    - Calling All Girls to the Skyways, American Weekly, 26 Sep 1954 (Oversize 4)
    - Christmas Stocking, undated; photocopy (Box 96)
    - Chuck Yeager: Aerospace Schoolmaster, Air Force and Space Digest, Jan 1963 (Box 96)
    - Cosmopolite of the Month and other articles, Cosmopolitan, 1941-1943 (Box 96)
      This is a bound volume containing the following Cosmopolitan articles:
      Cosmopolite of the Month: Alice Marble (Apr 1941)
      Lunch for 250,000 (July 1941)
      Where's Sammy? (by Sammy Schulman, edited by Considine) (Oct 1943)
      "Mission Complete" (Dec 1943)
    - Could You Have Loved as Much, Guideposts Magazine, Mar 1959 (Box 96)
    - Could You Have Loved as Much, Readers Digest, Apr 1966; photocopy (Box 96)
    - DC-8 Flight, Mainliner, Oct 1959 (Box 96)
    - The Daily Miracle, July 14, 1953; reprint of an "On the Line" column (Box 96)
    - Dateline: Olympics, The Ambassador, Spring 1960 (Box 96)
    - Dream Jobs, Redbook, Oct 1942 (Box 96)
    - Duffers Don't Fade -- Just Die, Golf, undated (Box 96)
    - Facts of After Life, Saturday Home Magazine, 1949 (Oversize 6)
    - Fortune Awaits Man Finding Secret of Lost Dutchman Gold Mine Near PHX, TWA Skyliner, 30 Mar 1950 (Box 96)
    - From One Ambassador to Another, TWA Ambassador, Dec 1957 (Box 96)
    - A Ghost Goes to Rest, True, Apr 1950 (Box 97)
    - God Love You, Cosmopolitan, July 1952; 2 copies (Box 97)
    - The Hardiest Breed, The American Way, Aug 1973 (Box 97)
    - How Ike Lives, The American Weekly, 1954; 5-part series on Eisenhower (Oversize 6)
    - How Tennis Players Get That Way, Cosmopolitan, May 1951 (Box 97)
    - I Should Have Bought More, Mutterings, Jan 1956; 2 copies (Box 97)
    - Inside Inside, Esquire, Jun 1951 (Oversize 6)
    - International News Service's 1956 Olympic Games Preview, special issue of INS Features, Nov 1956 (Box 97)
    - The Irish in Us, unknown source, Jun 1961 (Oversize 6)
    - It's a Rough One -- Isn't it? and other articles, True, 1944-1945 (Box 97)
      This is a bound volume containing the following True articles:
      It's a Rough One -- Isn't it?, by Bill McCarney as told to Considine (Feb 1945)
      War on the Kee Kee Bird (Apr 1945)
      Say it Ain't True, Joe (Sep 1944)
      Switch Artists (Oct 1944)
    - John Daly, Cosmopolitan, Jul 1954; 2 copies (Box 97)
    - The Kentucky Derby's Bill Corum, Collier's, 6 May 1950 (Oversize 6)
    - The Lively Ones, Signature, Dec 1969 (Box 97)
    - Luchow's is Different, The Restaurant Digest, Apr 1951; condensed from an undated Collier's article (Box 97)
    - Lunch with the General, Carnival, Spring/Summer 1951 (Box 97)
    - The Miracle at Your Front Door, Minneapolis Star and Tribune, undated; reprint of Considine column (Box 97)
    - Mission Complete, undated; 2 copies (Oversize 6)
    - Mr. Considine Writes an Open Letter, The Courier, 25 Feb 1957; Saint Rose Catholic High School, Belmar, NJ (Box 97)
    - Mutual of Omaha's Crusade Against Calamity, 13 May 1956; advertising supplement to the Sunday New York Times (Oversize 6)
    - My Favorite Column, Cosmopolitan, May 1950; 2 copies (Box 97)
    - My Favorite Column [A Newspaperman's Prayer], Diners' Club Magazine, Apr 1962 (Box 97)
    - My Hits -- and My Errors (by Babe Ruth with Bob Considine), Saturday Evening Post, 14 Feb 1948; 21 Feb 1948;; 13 Mar, 1948; five-part series; folder contains parts 1, 2, and 5 (Oversize 6)
    - The Navy Land War in China and other articles, Cosmopolitan, 1945-1946 (Box 98)
      The Navy Land War in China (Sep 1945)
      Chiang and the Chinese Puzzle (Oct 1945)
      Steve (Jan 1946)
      Magazine Pieces Don't Die (Apr 1946)
      Chic Young (July 1946)
    - The New Society in Sports, Flair, Jul 1950; 2 copies (Oversize 6)
    - Newspaperman's Prayer, reprint (Box 98)
    - On the Line [regarding Archbishop Paul Yu-Pin], The Call Board, Jun 1949 (Box 98)
    - On the Line, Eastern Tennis, Aug/Sep 1975; 2 copies (Box 98)
    - On the Louis-Schmeling Fight, Diners' Club Magazine, Mar 1963 (Box 98)
    - People, The American Way/American Way, 1974 Jun, Aug, Oct, Nov; 1975 Apr-Sep, Nov; column that ran in the publication; 8 articles; 2 folders (Box 98)
    - A Play for Glory and other articles, Collier's, 1937-1941 (Oversize 6)
      This is a bound volume containing the following Collier's articles:
      A Play for Glory (28 Aug 1937)
      Carefree Conqueror (Sep 11, 1938)
      Not a Clean Sweep (as told to Considine by Fred McDonald, June 4, 1938)
      End of the Rainbow (July 2, 1938)
      An Oscar for Love (July 1, 1939)
      Child's Play (Sep. 9, 1939), Foghorn (Apr. 13, 1940)
      Ivory from Cuba (Aug. 3, 1940)
      One-Two Punch (Sep. 28, 1940)
      Soose is no Goose (Jan. 11, 1941)
      Pro and Coin (Feb. 22, 1941)
      Old Bones (May 10, 1941)
    - Portrait of a Prelate, Boston Sunday Advertiser, 19 Oct 1958 (Oversize 7)
    - A President has Damned Few Friends, This Week, 24 Aug 1968 (Oversize 7)
    - Pride Goeth Before... (Box 98)
    - The Professionals, in an advertisement for the National Football League (Box 98)
    - Robert L. Ripley, The Modern Marco Polo, True, Nov 1961 (Box 98)
    - El Robo de la Bomba Atomica, parts 1 and 2, Bohemia, 20 Jan 1952; 27 Jan 1952; Spanish translation in Cuban magazine; 2 folders (Oversize 7)
    - Russia's Ally -- The Wrong Letter from Home, Cosmopolitan, Nov 1951; 2 copies (Box 98)
    - The Shame of Litchfield, True, Jul 1947 (Box 98)
    - Spectators Without Calluses, Liberty, 12 Apr 1947 (Box 98)
    - Summer is Hell for Millions of People, House Beautiful, undated; reprint, 2 copies (Box 98)
    - Sweden Watches the Sky, Cosmopolitan, Jan 1947 (Box 99)
    - The 10 Most Colorful Men I've Met, American Weekly, 26 Apr 1959 (Oversize 7)
    - Theatre World Wide, The Call Board, Jun 1958 (Box 99)
    - Those Were the Days My Friend, The American Way, Apr 1972 (Box 99)
    - To Donnycove, through Killbegs, Kilkerry and Kildare, Saturday Review, 17 Mar 1962; 2 copies (Box 99)
    - To Smoke or not to Smoke, Cosmopolitan, Apr 1954 (Box 99)
    - Tomorrow is too Late, The American Weekly, 7 Jun 1953; 2 copies (Oversize 7)
    - A Tribute to Courage, Cancer News, Oct 1952; reprinted from a previous INS column (Box 99)
    - Walter Cronkite: A Personal Perspective, American Way, Dec 1975 (Box 99)
    - Walter Cronkite: Transitions, American Way, Jan 1976 (Box 99)
    - Washington Hostess, undated (Box 99)
    - We Can Bury, You, Mr. K, Readers Digest, Jul 1962; condensed from article that ran in New York Journal-American, 2 copies (Box 99)
    - We Caught Them Off Saipan, as told to Considine by Ben Tate, Cosmopolitan, Dec 1944 (Box 99)
    - We Light the Target and other articles, Cosmopolitan, 1944-1945 (Box 99)
      We Light the Target and other articles, with Richard A. Wellington (Mar 1944)
      An Island We Had to Take (as told to Considine by Gilbert Bundy, Nov 1944)
      We Caught Them Off Saipan (as told to Considine by Ben Tate, Dec 1944)
      God Said "Bail Out!" (with Arthur S. Ross, Feb 1945)
    - Well, A Little More Time…, Collier's, 24 Dec 1949; 2 copies (Oversize 7)
    - Well, A Little More Time… with 'The Nativity', reprint from Mutual of Omaha; read on Mutual of Omaha's Bob Considine Show, broadcast Dec. 22, 1951 (Oversize 7)
    - Well, A Little More Time…, reprint from Mutual of Omaha; read on Mutual of Omaha's Bob Considine Show, broadcast Dec. 19, 1954 (Oversize 7)
    - Well, A Little More Time…, undated; with printed note, "Merry Christmas Happy New Year from all the Considines" (Oversize 7)
    - Where's Sammy?, by Sammy Schilman and edited by Considine, Cosmopolitan, Oct 1943 (Box 99)
    - With Nixon in China… Visit to a Peking Pharmacy, American Druggist, 3 Apr 1972; photocopy, galley proof (Box 99)
    - Word Tribute to a Beloved Picture Man, National Press Photographer, Apr 1957 (Box 99)
  - Articles about Considine
    - Breig, Joe, "Mr. Bob Considine and Hot Cross Buns", 3 May 1958 (Box 99)
    - Dulan, Jimmy, "Considine Gets the Headline Stories," The Catholic Boy, Jun 1953 (Box 99)
    - Gehman, Richard, "On the Line with Considine," Catholic Digest, Dec 1958 (Box 99)
    - Paye, Paul, "Wanted: Catholic Journalists," Catholic Boy, Feb 1963 (Box 99)
    - Storer, Douglas, "After Dark Reporter," View [in the Albany Times Union], 1 Jun 1957 (Box 99)
    - Sulivan, Frank, "The Dutch Treat Club," Lincoln-Mercury Times, Mar/Apr 1952 (Box 99)
    - Unknown author, "Bob Considine to Give Special Report from Monaco, " The Nebraska Newspaper, Apr 1956 (Box 100)
    - Miscellaneous material about Considine from Dateline, the magazine of the Overseas Press Club of America, 1958; 1959,; 1962 (Box 100)
    - Miscellaneous material about Considine (Box 100)
    - Miscellaneous material about Considine, oversize (Oversize 15)
  - Articles by Millie Considine
    - Celebrities at Play, The Diplomat, Jul 1954 (Box 100)
  - Articles by others